Cecil Thomas, MCT

Taylorsville, UT 84129 (435) 668-2486 me@cecil-thomas.com github.com/kitsune21

Detailed and Focused Web Developer, who likes to build cool things.

WEBSITES/PROJECTS

Journeys.Cafe - A web app that is mobile friendly that allows users to create and share travel itinerary plans. Integrates with several services to allow for authentication, document/image uploads, monthly/yearly subscriptions, weather information, and currency conversion information.

Cecil-Thomas.com - Built using React.js with Typescript. Over 80% unit test coverage. Uses a custom built terminal-like interface to allow the users to execute commands to learn more about myself, and projects that I have worked on.

Frozenspade.Tv - Built using React.js and hosted on Netlify. Uses the SpeedRun.com api to pull in data on currently held world records for the Twitch streamer "Frozenspade". Full CI/CD pipeline between GitHub and Netlify to allow for rapid deployments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MRIoA, Salt Lake City — Web Developer

May 2024 - Current

- Worked on projects to convert older C++ apps into web apps using React and Node.js.
- Introduced build tools for React apps that improved build times by 50+%.

Entrata, Lehi — *Software Developer 1*

March 2021 - October 2023

- Led the prototyping and development of the first new features using React/Typescript to speed up the user experience.
- Worked on projects that refactored the codebase for maintainability.
- Added unit test coverage using the PHPUnit framework.

SKILLS

ReactJS

NodeJS

TypeScript

TailwindCSS

PostgreSQL

C#

AWS

Ruby on Rails

PHP

AWARDS

Eagle Scout Rank

Louis Armstrong Jazz

Award

John Phillips Sousa Award

LANGUAGES

English

Japanese

Spanish

Entrata, Lehi - Software Development Manager

June 2020 - March 2021

- Managed a project to remove a dependency on a third-party api, and replace it with our own custom built micro-service. Which saved thousands of dollars.
- Worked with my teams to reduce the open bug backlog from over 100 to less than 20.
- Facilitated development of new products that leveraged machine learning.

EDUCATION

DevPoint Labs, Salt Lake City

Aug 2019 - October 2019